ゴゴレツゴレツゴ伊達工
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
Go, go, let's go! Let's go Date Tech!
Attack! Attack, attack, attack, attack, Seijou!
Well?! Are they winning?!
どうだ勝てるか
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigamiorg)制作仅供交流学习禁止用于任何商业用途
Stop pushing!
押すな
Date Tech                 Aoba Jousai
日听：小伍King翻译：森罗小江校对：Syura时间轴：海底压制：Coolkid
At least the lead is only two points.
いやまだたたの２点差だし
They're in the second set.
今２セト目か
Who took the first set?
１セト目はどちが獲たんだ
Um...
Apparently Seijou won the first set.
１セト目は青城が獲たぽいです
Ah, Karasuno!
烏野
H-Hey there...
どどうもちわす
Hey.
ちわす
こんちわす
Heyo.
ちわす
Hello!
Hey.
Karasuno's got some third-years left.
烏野は３年残てんだな
Yeah.
Now, how is our new team doing?
さあうちの新チムはどうだ
Makki!
Yeah!
よしゃ
Damn, they're seeing right through them.
くそちゃんと見えてやがる
Rule the Court
Great, great, Takahiro!
Push it, push it, Takahiro! Do it again!
いぞいぞタカヒロ押せ押せタカヒロもう一本
Date Tech                 Aoba Jousai
Give us a good one, Hanamaki!
花巻ナイサ
Sorry!
すまん
Kogane!
黄金
Got it!
オライ
Date Tech has a new setter.
伊達工のセタ新しい奴だな
Yeah.
どんなトスを
I wonder what kind of set he'll...
What the heck was that?!
なんだあのトス
Episode Nineteen:
The Iron Wall Can Be Built Again and Again
飞吧FlyHigh汗水与血泪交织
Kogane!
黄金
一点点一步步
闪耀的翅膀带你去往任何地方
翱翔于高空之中向着最遥远的未来
凭着青涩的冲动与本能翱翔于天空之上
飞吧FlyHigh汗水与血泪交织
翱翔于高空之中向着最遥远的未来
在梦想实现之前困难的旅途也不足为惧飞吧Fly
展开闪耀的翅膀将一切置于身后Fly
不理会低空飞行的鸟儿的嘲笑只想眺望海的尽头
满身伤痕的雏鸟凝视天空
浑然忘我迎着逆风开始助跑
Got it!
オライ
Yeah! Go!
よし行け
Kogane's movements still seem rough.
黄金は動きがまだ素人くさいな
Well, as long as the ball goes up.
まぁ上がりゃ問題ねぇよ
Left!
レフト
Okay!
What the heck was that?!
なんだあのトス
二口先輩お願いします
I'm counting on you, Futakuchi!
It's too high!
高けぇよ
I'm not good with high sets!
俺高すぎんの苦手なんだよ
All right!
よしゃ
Sorry!
ごめん
Good job, guys!
Shake it off, Futakuchi!
二口先輩ドンマイス
Y-You need to set it a little lower, Koganegawa.
もう少し低くだ黄金川
Right! Lower!
ウス低くスね
Don't make it too low, though. I need it in between.
低すぎずだぞ中くらいだ中くらい
Right!
Do you really understand that?
ホントにわかてんだろうな
Of course!
もちろんス
Olé!
Sorry.
ごめん
No worries!
ドンマイです
Date Tech's setter is a first-year, right?
伊達工のセタて１年だよなあの７番
Yeah.
He's really tall...
デカいよな
ワンタチ
I hit it!
Yeah, he is.
おおデカいな
That's our new weapon.
アレはうちの新兵器
The giant setter, Koganegawa.
大型セタ黄金川です
Giant...
大型
...setter?
Huh?
Nice catch!
ナイスキャチ
I'm sorry! I'll do a hundred laps
around the school to make up for it!
スンマセン校庭１００周してお詫びします
You should be practicing setting with that time!
そこはトス練しろよ
H-He's still learning!
ままだ発展途上なんスよ
He just became a setter!
セタになて間もないんで
He'll be a huge deal eventually!
これから大物になるんで
Th-Those kinds of mistakes happen all the time...
あのくらいのミスはよくありますよ
Well, um, he really has good potential! It's true!
いやあの底がすごくいいんスよホントに
You're making Karasuno's captain take pity on you, Moniwa.
烏野の主将に気ィ使わせてんぞ茂庭
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
I used to be pretty cheeky,
so I'm sure I was quite a pain for my upperclassmen,
俺生意気だたから
先輩達はさぞ面倒くさかただろうなと思うけど
Bring it!
さ来い
All right, bring it!
よしゃ来いや
but I think being too serious all the time is a problem too.
真面目すぎんのもどうかと思うわ
Futakuchi is having trouble with his junior.
あの二口が後輩に手を焼いてる
Serves him right!
ざまぁ
Date Tech             Aoba Jousai
Give us a good serve, Matsukawa!
松川ナイサ
They can't afford to let them extend the lead.
これ以上点差つけられたくない
Bring it!
さ来い
You guys gotta stop it before it starts.
一本で切れよ
Left!
レフト
He's going for a setter dump,
and he's up high above the block, but...
ツのモション高いブロクの上
it's completely obvious!
バレバレだ
Huh?
Damn it.
Here's our chance!
チャンスチャンス
Iwa!
岩ちゃん
作並ナイス
Nice, Sakunami!
Finish it, Futakuchi!
二口ラスト
I touched it!
ワンチ
Got it!
オライ
Makki!
Okay!
Number three, a wing spiker, is going to set?
３番のウィングスパイカの人がトスを
Oikawa!
及川
及川さん
どりゃあ
Shake it off.
ドンマイ
Nice block, Kogane!
黄金ナイスブロク
Learn to hold back, you idiot!
加減しろやこのヤロウォ
Right! Sorry!
ウスすんません二口先輩大丈夫スか
Are you okay, Futakuchi?!
No, I'm not! That's why I'm
telling you to learn to hold back!
大丈夫じゃねぇから加減しろつたんだよ
It's my fault for not being able to support everyone.
俺が支えきれなかたのが悪い
You were fine.
今のでいい
Yessir!
That...
アレがうちの
is our new Iron Wall, Koganegawa.
新しい鉄壁黄金川です
New...
新しい
...Iron Wall.
鉄壁
He reworded it because it didn't work out so well earlier.
さきのがイマイチキマんなかたから言い直したな
Looks like we're up against an annoying team again.
また面倒くさいチムと当たたもんだ
To be honest, that was sort of refreshing.
正直ちょとスカとしたな
True.
確かに
I can hear you, you know!
聞こえてから
Now then, what to do?
さてどうしたもんかな
Nice receive!
ナイスレシブ
どりゃあ
Got it!
オライ
金田一
Kindaichi!
A counterattack!
カウンタ
All right!
よしゃ
They really are good.
さすがだな
There you go again! It's way too obvious!
またおめぇはよバレバレなんだよ
Sorry, but a setter dump looks really cool,
so I can't help myself!
すんませんでもツアタクかけぇからやりたいんス
And that's why it's so obvious.
わかりやすい理由だ
Look, you don't need to tip it over when you do a setter dump.
つかお前ツの時フェイントじゃなくていいだろ
Huh?
What?
Date Tech             Aoba Jousai
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
C'mon, Oikawa!
及川さんナイサ
Olé!
Rule the Court
All right!
よしゃ
押せ押せトオルもう一本
It looks like Seijou has the upper hand.
やぱり青城の方が一枚上手て感じなんすかね
Date Tech is still flailing around.
伊達工の方はまだバタバタするもんな
Once their giant setter settles in,
I'm sure he'll be an amazing weapon.
大型セタハマたらすごい武器なんだろうけどな
Give us another good serve, Oikawa!
及川もう一本ナイサ
Olé!
Damn it!
It's going over the net!
ネト越える
Here's our chance!
チャンスボル
Another fast attack is coming!
また速攻来るぞ
Left!
レフト
Center!
センタ
Number twelve!
１２番１２番
Listen up.
いいか
Koganegawa's basically still a baby as a setter.
黄金川はセタとしてまだ赤子同然だ
So you need to literally guide him along, Sakunami.
まずはお前が文字通り導いてやれ作並
Go somewhere convenient for Koganegawa...
黄金川くんが得意な場所へ
and receive!
レシブ
Good!
When you receive the ball,
get it high enough for Koganegawa to do a jumping set.
レシブは黄金川がジャンプトスできる十分な高さで上げてやれ
It doesn't matter how close it is to the net.
多少ネトに近くなてもいい
He'll get it.
こいつは
届く
You don't need to try anything fancy yet.
お前は今はまだ難しいことをやろうとしなくていい
Just get it from one high place...
高い場所から高い場所へ
...to another!
置いてくるだけ
Nice spike, Aone!
Date Tech             Aoba Jousai
いぞいぞ青根
いぞいぞ青根いぞいぞ青根
So fast! So high!
速ぇ高ぇ
He put it right where the spiker was going to hit it.
まさに打点に置くだけて感じですね
That's definitely a combo that's only possible because of how high up the setter can get.
セタ自身の最高到達点が高いからこそできるコンビネションだな
Nice set, Kogane!
黄金ナイストス
A set that takes advantage of his height...
デカいことを生かしたトスか
Thanks!
あざす
That huge setter's pretty interesting.
面白いじゃん大型セタ
!!
Haikyuu
Second Season
H
a
S
e
i
c
k
y
o
n
u
d
S
e
!
a
s
o
n
ゴゴレツゴレツゴ伊達工
Date Tech             Aoba Jousai
Go, go, let's go! Let's go, Date Tech!
We're gonna catch up!
追いつけるぞ
ここでブロク一本だ
Get a block here!
Give us a good serve, Jingo!
仁悟ナイサ
オライ
Got it!
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
よしゃ
Yeah!
A setter dump!
ここでツ
And I was just thinking how he was laying low today.
今日は鳴りを潜めてるなと思てたら
Gotta say he's pretty calm.
さすがに冷静だな
It's infuriating.
腹立つ
あと一点あと一点あと一点あと一点
Date Tech                 Aoba Jousai
One more point! One more point!
ここで青城のマチポイントか
Now Seijou is at match point.
落ち着いてまずは一本切てこう
Calm down!
Take it one point at a time!
Right!
ウス/オス
Give us a good serve, Hanamaki!
花巻ナイサ
Olé!
Nice!
青城全体のサブのレベル上がてんな
ナイス
Seijou has gotten better at serving as a whole.
Cover it!
Yeah.
Left!
レフト
Futakuchi!
二口さん
All right!
Go, Futakuchi!
二口行け
しゃぁ
Yeah!
よしゃ
All right!
You see our juniors?!
うちの後輩見たかコラァ見とけコラァクラァ
You'd better be watching!
行け行け二口
And now, their first-year setter is back in the front row.
ここであの１年セタくん前衛か
All right!
よしゃあ
Give us a good serve, Onagawa!
女川先輩ナイサ
エスでブロクも上手い二口
Futakuchi's the ace and also good at blocking.
It goes without saying that Aone is the core of the Iron Wall.
言わずもがな「鉄壁の中枢」青根
そして３枚目黄金川
And then there's the third section, Koganegawa.
間違いなく今現在県内最強の「３枚壁」だ
Without a doubt, right now, they're the best wall of three blockers in the prefecture.
Give us a good one!
ナイサ
Sorry! It's a bit short!
ごめん少し短い
岩ちゃん
Iwa!
Yeah!
I hit it!
ワンタチ
パンタロン
Pants!
オライ
Got it!
Kogane!
黄金
Right!
つかお前
Look, you don't need to tip it over when you do a setter dump.
ツの時フェイントじゃなくていいだろ
Huh?
What?
ブ叩け
Slam it down.
Whoa! This time, he smashed it down!
よし一本決また
今度はツで強打か
Even if you saw it coming, it'd be impossible to dig out.
読んでても拾えないすね
行け行け黄金
よしゃブレイクも一本行けぇ
Yeah! Do it again!
All right! Two in a row!
Date Tech                 Aoba Jousai
Hey.
Hm?
いつも通りでいい
Just play normally.
俺に勝負させろ
I'll take them on.
Roger that!
ウィス
あと一点あと一点あと一点あと一点
Oikawa set the ball away from the net to avoid it getting blocked, right?
さき及川はブロクに捕まらないよう
トスをネトから離したんですね
岩泉はお気に召さなかたみたいだな
Looks like Iwaizumi wasn't too fond of that move.
Well, it does make it harder to hit.
まあ打ちづらくもなりますからね
もう一点
One more point!
Give us a good serve!
ナイサ
Got it!
オライ
Nice receive, Saku!
作くんナイスレシブ
But it's gonna go over the net!
でもネト越えちゃう
It's up!
上がた
ラスト１点
Just one more!
Someone get it!
End it here!
これで決めろ
Stop it!
止めろ
渡すな
Don't let them have it!
Iwa!
岩ちゃん
Yeah!
俺はセタとしてまだ赤子同然
Right now, I'm basically a baby as a setter.
今の俺が先輩たちと同等に持てるものがあるとするなら
If there's anything that I'm not currently lacking compared to my upperclassmen,
it's my height!
高さのみ
ここで終わて
We're not going to let it...
たまるか
end here!
締めが甘いぜ１年坊主
Your resolve is weak,
you first-year brat!
It...
う腕のど真ん中抜いた
It went right between his arms!
しゃあ
Yes!
すげぇぞ岩泉
That was awesome, Iwaizumi!
かこいいやつめ
You awesome guy!
岩泉さんすげぇす
You're amazing, Iwaizumi!
Nice spike.
ナイスキ
俺もまだまだすな
I guess I still have a lot to learn.
あの３枚ブロク相手に真向勝負
He took those three blockers head-on.
悔しいけどかこいいぜ
I hate to admit it, but that was awesome.
Date Tech             Aoba Jousai
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much for the match!
次の相手
I guess we know who we'll face next.
決またな
整列
Line up.
Ugh!
げて何だ二口このヤロウ
What do you mean, "ugh"?! Futakuchi, you asshole!
You still suck, Kogane!
まだまだヘタクソだな黄金
I'm sorry!
すんません
And you totally have your hands full, Mr. New Captain.
新キャプテンは全然余裕ねぇしな
Do you understand how important Moniwa was now?
茂庭のありがたみが分かたか
I've known his worth for a while.
そんなの前から分かてます
Good grief...
またく
I see nothing but room for growth!
伸び代しかねぇな
And there's definitely a lot of room to grow.
それも超長ぇ伸び代な
Keep working hard. Work even harder than you have been.
頑張れ今よりももとだ
You guys can form the best Iron Wall yet.
お前たちなら歴代最強の鉄壁になれる
じゃ行きましょうか
Let's go, then.
Huh?
茂庭さんたちこんなところ来てるてことは
The fact that you guys are here means you have time on your hands, right?
時間あるんですよね
戻て練習相手してください
Let's go back so you can practice with us.
What?
I guess we don't have much of a choice!
しょうがねぇな
ここで脱ぐなよ
Don't start stripping here.
Kamasaki, you haven't bulked up so much that you can't jump anymore, have you?
鎌先さん筋肉盛りすぎてジャンプできなくなてないですか
Huh? What do you mean?
なんで
Well, muscles are heavy.
筋肉て重いんですよ
えマジすか
What? Really?
俺
I'll...
I'll get to the point where I can set any ball that comes my way!
どんなボルでも上げられるようになります
And I'll be able to block!
それにブロクも
鉄壁の名に恥じないように
So that I won't shame the title of the Iron Wall, I'll make sure I'm able to stop anyone,
どんなパワなやつでもでかいやつでも
no matter how big or strong they are!
止められるようになります
Opponents that are hard to stop aren't always big or strong.
止めることの難しい相手が
大きく力が強いとは限らない
日向翔陽次は必ず
Hinata Shouyou...
I'll make sure to stop you next time.
お前を止める
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
な何だか皆さんピリピリしてます
I-Is everyone on edge for some reason?
Last time, they gave their all against Aoba Jousai,
前回青葉城西には全力出し切て
yet they still lost.
それでも負けたから
や谷地さん
Y-Yachi.
Yes?!
胃薬てあるかな
Do you have any antacids?
Are you all right, Yamaguchi?!
山口くん大丈夫
Shimizu!
清水
ごめんちょと緊張しちゃて
Sorry, I'm just a little nervous.
I-I'm pretty confident when it comes to being nervous!
私緊張にかけては結構自信あるんだ
Huh? Confident about being nervous?
自信緊張に
It's better to say something than keep it bottled up.
緊張はね口に出したほうがいいんだよ
You'll feel much better if you instead say, "I'm so nervous! What should I do?!"
我慢するより
緊張するどうしようて素直に言ちゃたほうが心が解れるんだよ
I often experience live-threatening fear because of my nerves, so I've done a lot of research.
私よく緊張による命の危険を感じるから
いろいろ調べたんだ
Life-threatening?
命の危険
Like sports festivals or tests!
体育祭とかテストとか
Tests?
テスト
Well...
俺
Yes?
インハイ予選の青城戦
In our interhigh prelims match against Seijou,
when the team was in trouble,
チムがピンチの時
初めてピンチサバで試合出たんだ
I was brought in as a pinch server for the first time.
Aoba Jousai                    Karasuno
We were only down a few points.
追いつけない点差じゃなかた
If I'd landed the serve, we might've been able to win.
俺が決めてたら勝てたかもしれない
なのに俺はミスて
But I blew it.
When I think about that happening again...
だからまたそうなたらと思うと
You...
そんなチムのピンチを任されたと
You were put in charge of something that important?!
谷地さん
Yachi?!
緊張してきた心臓出る
I'm so nervous!
It feels like my heart is going to come right out of my mouth!
口から出る
Swallow it down!
の飲み込んで胃薬いる
Do you need antacids?
A heart stimulant?! An AED?!
救心AED
どうした
What's going on?!
Yachi's heart!
谷地さんの心臓が心臓が
Her heart!
Calm down, Yamaguchi!
落ち着け山口
１１０番か
Should we call the cops?!
You mean an ambulance?
１１９番ですよ
おい月島どこ行くんだよ
Hey, where're you going?
風邪みたいに緊張も他人に感染したら治るのかな
I wonder if nerves are like a cold and you get better when you give it to someone else.
You all seem better than before.
皆さきより元気
何真面目に分析してんだよ
Why are you trying to explain this rationally?
影山くんもまさかのビビリタイムですか
Are you freaking out before the match too, Kageyama?
Yeah.
Oikawa's really good.
及川さんは強ぇからな
You sure can't handle the Great King, huh?
お前本当大王様苦手な
Well, not like it's any different for me.
ま俺もだけど
You were looking forward to taking him on, weren't you?
戦うの楽しみにしてたじゃねぇか
ビビるもんはビビるんだよ
You can't control what freaks you out.
"The team that's better as six is better."
６人で強いほうが強い
Huh?
昔岩泉さんが及川さんに言たのを聞いた
I overheard Iwaizumi say that to Oikawa once.
The team that's better as six is better, dumbass!
６人で強いほうが強いんだろうがボケが
At the time, I was wondering why he said something so obvious.
あの時は何を当然のことを言てんだて思た
Of course a team of six good players would be good.
強いメンバが６人揃てりゃ強いに決まてんのにて
But now I really understand him.
でも今になて分かる
Iwaizumi wasn't talking about
adding everyone's strengths together.
岩泉さんが言たのはメンバの力を足し算じゃなく
He was talking about multiplying them.
いかに掛け算できるかてことだたんだ
どんなチムに入ても
No matter what team he's on, Oikawa can draw out the strength of each spiker better than I can.
及川さんは俺よりスパイカの力を引き出す
Really?
そうなの
Even if you're right...
そうだとしても
that only applies to teams other than us!
烏野以外はだな
よし皆いるな
Okay, is everyone here?
It's almost time.
そろそろ時間だ
All right, let's go!
よし行くぞ
しゃあ
Yeah!
默默无闻之辈眼中闪烁着光辉
We're going to get revenge...
茫茫夜色之中孤身一人也无妨
...with our new fast attack!
I'd like another pork cutlet bowl, ma'am!
哪怕天空没有一丝星光也想伸手远方
You're eating way too much. That's your fourth one!
In order for me to become the best Iron Wall,
I'm gonna try to grow until I reach two meters tall!
期待会否落空已不是我心中所想
What you need to grow is your skills, not your height.
Episode Twenty:
Sweep Clear
就这样深呼吸倾听心口的跃动一切都独一无二
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
"Sweep Clear."
站在苍白的舞台上追求到底不放弃
谁都没有见过的那轮朝阳即将升起
嘶力竭
问问自己的内心
我们在这籍籍无名的世界上努力
追寻那道似曾相识的朝阳霞光
那些无法回头的岁月化作光阴的证明
问问自己的内心
押せ押せ押せ押せ押せ青城
行け行け行け行け行け青城
俺たちの新速攻で
リベンジだ
おばちゃんカツ丼おかわり
食いすぎだろ４杯目だぞ
俺最強の鉄壁になるために
目一杯伸びて２メトル目指します
いやお前が伸ばさなきゃいけないのは技術のほうだろ
次回ハイキュ払拭